(305) 988-3494

# Ruby Romeu – Full Stack Engineer

Yes, Ruby, like the programming language. Sattar is my Maiden name. I'm an engineer in the Greater Boston Area who has built multiple full-stack applications. Using software development as well as my background in education, my goal is to impact educational technology and the future of tech resources available in underserved communities.

Website
rubysattar.github.io
Github
github.com/rubysattar
Email
rubysattar@gmail.com

## SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

## General Assembly, Boston - Engineering Fellow JUNE 2020 - SEP 2020

General Assembly is an immersive program that prepares software engineers with a holistic technical foundation essential for full-stack development.

- Built full-stack applications for teachers and currently conducting user research for continued iteration.
- Incorporated functionality from 3rd-party APIs to add complexity and nuance.

## **STEM ENRG, Boston - Engineering Mentee** SEP 2020 - PRESENT

A 6-month program to create economic equity for women of color in STEM careers through mentorship, leadership training, and collaboration in the tech industry.

## **PROJECTS**

**OverAchiever** — A flashcard learning application [Python, Django, React, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, SCSS]

**The Holistic Educator** — A classroom connections tracking application [Mongoose, Express, MongoDB, Javascript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, SCSS]

**Education Donation Store**— *E-Commerce Team project/application* [Mongoose, Express, React|S, Javascript, Bootstrap, SCSS]

### OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KIPP Academy, Boston - Lead Teacher FEB 2018 - JUNE 2020

KIPP is a mission-driven school where teachers regularly collaborate..

- Led a DEI workshop for a team of 30+ educators and school leaders, resulting in actionable commitments for the school environment
- Designed a K-8 Women's History curriculum with G-Suite tech resources.
- Utilized Tableau to analyze data and inform instruction

The Mildred (BPS), Boston - Lead Teacher OCT 2017 - FEB 2018

**SFPCC of Harvard, Boston - Lead Teacher** AUG 2015 - MAY 2017

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

Javascript MongoDB
React NoSQL
jQuery Node.js
Mongoose Express.js
CSS/Sass Bootstrap
Django SQL/NoSQL

**RESTful API's** 

### **SKILLS**

Cross-industry technology
Teamwork
Leadership
Trouble-shooting
Communication

Coaching

## **EDUCATION**

LinkedIn Learning — Certificates NOV 2019

HTML, CSS, SCRUM

Florida International University, Miami — Bachelor's

MAY 2012 - DECEMBER 2014

Magna Cum Laude, Honors, 200+ hours of field research on ed-tech in school settings.